datacamp.com 2019-07-10

# Privacy Policy | DataCamp

## Before We Get Started

### Whose privacy policy is this?

This Privacy Policy applies to the website accessible at https://www.datacamp.com, the e-learning platform also accessible through that website, the DataCamp Community website and the mobile application, all owned and operated by DataCamp, Inc., a Delaware limited liability company.

When we refer to ‘we’ (“DataCamp”, ”we”, or “us”), that means DataCamp Inc. and all its wholly-owned subsidiaries. Our headquarters are in New York City but we operate and have offices all over the world.

For European Union data protection purposes, when we act as a controller in relation to your personal data, DataCamp Belgium BVBA (company number 0542351249) is our representative in the European Union.

If you use our service though a Free Plan or Individual Plan, we are the **data controller** of your personal data. This means we request and collect your personal data and vouch to work responsibly with it. We put the necessary security measurements in place, give you full control over your personal data, and we respect your rights as the owner of your personal data.

If you are using our service as part of a Business Plan or Classroom Plan, DataCamp is the **data processor** of your personal data. The organization that contracted with us for the subscription is the data controller.

This privacy policy is part of our Terms of Use. Terms used but not defined in this privacy policy have the meanings provided in the Terms of Use.

* * *

### What is personal data?

Personal data identifies you as a person, such as your name, postal address, email address or telephone number. It allows us to know who you are. Later in this policy we will explain which personal data we collect. Use the menu to your left to start exploring what data we collect for each goal.

* * *

### What if we change this policy?

We may need to update this policy from time to time so we encourage you to review it frequently. If you are unsure if the policy has changed, please refer to the “Last Modified” date below. If a change is significant, we will post a notice on the datacamp.com website and in the DataCamp app before such changes take effect and send a notice via email giving you the flexibility to terminate your contract with us or opt-out of certain aspects, such as receiving emails.

Last modified on May 25, 2018.

* * *

### Do we collect personal data from children?

We do not intentionally gather personal data from visitors who are under the age of 16. If you believe that we might have done so, please contact us using our privacy contact form. When we learn that a child under 16 has submitted their personal data to DataCamp, we will try to delete the information as soon as possible if we do not have consent from the guardian.

* * *

### Do we transfer data outside of your country?

Your information, including personal data that we collect from you, will be transferred to, stored at, and processed by us and other third parties (documented within this policy) outside of the country in which you reside, including, but not limited to the United States. By using our services you agree to this transfer, storing, and processing.

We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this policy.

* * *

### Is my data being shared outside of DataCamp?

In some cases, we share some of your personal data with external services that we need to run our own services. These services are mentioned near the respective data type in the table above and in other sections.

Regardless of any choices you make regarding your personal data, Datacamp may disclose personal data if it believes in good faith that such disclosure is necessary (i) in connection with any legal investigation; (ii) to comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on Datacamp; (iii) to protect or defend the rights or property of Datacamp or users of the Site or Services; and/or (iv) to investigate or assist in preventing any violation or potential violation of the law, this policy, or our Terms of Use.

Other than that we do not share your personal data with any other party. We are not selling or trading your personal data with any third party.

* * *

### How long is my data being kept?

As long as you are an active user on DataCamp we keep your personal data. However, we realize that users come and go and we don’t want to keep sitting on your personal data forever. That is why we actively try to monitor your activity and when we realize you became inactive, we will try to reactivate you by sending you a few notifications (by email or in our apps). When we get no response we will automatically remove your personal data.

We see inactivity as someone that hasn’t signed in during the last 1.5 years. Typically this means that after noticing that you are a non-active and non-paying user for 1.5 years, we will remind you of your account. After trying a few times without response, we will delete your personal data permanently.

* * *

### How do we protect your personal data?

The security of your personal data is important to us. We seek to use reasonable organizational, technical, and administrative measures to protect personal data within our organization:

  * When you enter sensitive data (such as a credit card number), your information is sent over an authenticated and encrypted connection using [Transport Layer Security](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transport_Layer_Security) (TLS).
  * We store your personal data only on servers with limited access that are located in controlled facilities and use a variety of technologies and procedures intended to protect your personal information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.

Nonetheless, no communication via the Internet can ever be 100% secure, and no security measures are guaranteed to be effective. Accordingly, you are advised to use caution and discretion when determining what personal information to disclose to us.

If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify us of the problem by contacting us via our privacy contact form.

* * *

### What about links to third party websites?

The service may contain links to third party websites. When you click on a link to any other website or location, you will go to another site, and another entity may collect personal or anonymous data from you. We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for these outside websites or their content. Please be aware that this privacy policy does not apply to these outside websites or content, or to any collection of your personal data after you click on links to such outside websites. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of every website you visit. The links to third party websites or locations are for your convenience and do not signify our endorsement of such third parties or their products, content, or websites.

* * *

### Should I share sensitive personal data while using the service?

We ask that you not send us and that you do not disclose any sensitive personal data (e.g., social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or other beliefs, health information, biometrics or genetic characteristics, criminal background or trade union membership) on or through the services or otherwise to us. If you send or disclose any sensitive personal data to us when you submit user generated content to the services, you consent to our processing and use of such sensitive personal data in accordance with this policy. If you do not consent to our processing and use of such sensitive personal data, you must not submit such content.

* * *

### What if DataCamp is acquired or if we acquire another company?

We may share some or all of your personal data in connection with or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisition or dissolution transaction or proceeding involving sale, transfer, divestiture, or disclosure of all or a portion of our business or assets.

In the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership, personal data may also be transferred as a business asset.

If another company acquires our company, business, or assets, that company will possess the personal data collected by us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your personal data as described in this policy.

Upon these events, this policy might change and we will notify you when appropriate.
